<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proportional Hazards on Paul C. Lambert</title>
    <link>/tags/proportional-hazards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proportional Hazards on Paul C. Lambert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Paul C Lambert</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/proportional-hazards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity analysis to location of knots (proportional hazards)</title>
      <link>/software/stpm2/knot_positions_sensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stpm2/knot_positions_sensitivity/</guid>
      <description>Sensitivity analysis to the location of knots When using stpm2 with the df() option the location of the knots for the restricted cubic splines are selected using the defaults. These are the based at the centiles of $\ln(t)$ for the events (i.e. the non censored observations). The boundary knots are placed at the minimum and maximum log event times. For example, with 5 knots there will be knots placed at the $0^{th}$, $25^{th}$, $50^{th}$, $75^{th}$, and $100^{th}$ centiles of the log event times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of the timevar() option</title>
      <link>/software/stpm2/stpm2_timevar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stpm2/stpm2_timevar/</guid>
      <description>Background In this tutorial I will describe some simple use of the timevar() option when obtaining predictions after fitting a model using stpm2. When using Stata&amp;rsquo;s survival models, such as streg and stcox, predictions are made at the values of _t, which is each record&amp;rsquo;s event or censoring time. This is the default behaviour of stpm2.
One of the advantages of parametric survival models is that we can predict various quantities (hazard, survival functions etc etc) at any value of time and for any covariate pattern as we have an equation which is a function of time and any covariates we have modelled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proportional hazards models in stpm2</title>
      <link>/software/stpm2/comparewithcox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stpm2/comparewithcox/</guid>
      <description>Proportional hazards model We first load the example breast cancer data data using webuse and then use stset to declare the survival time and event indicator.
. webuse brcancer, clear (German breast cancer data) . stset rectime, f(censrec==1) scale(365.24) failure event: censrec == 1 obs. time interval: (0, rectime] exit on or before: failure t for analysis: time/365.24 ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 686 total observations 0 exclusions ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 686 observations remaining, representing 299 failures in single-record/single-failure data 2,112.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity analysis to number of knots (proportional hazards)</title>
      <link>/software/stpm2/sensitivity_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stpm2/sensitivity_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Sensitivity Analysis We first load the example Rotterdam breast cancer data (rott2b.dta) and then use stset to declare the survival time (relapse free survival) and event indicator. Follow-up is restricted to 5 years using the exit() option.
. use https://www.pclambert.net/data/rott2b, clear (Rotterdam breast cancer data (augmented with cause of death)) . stset rf, f(rfi==1) scale(12) exit(time 60) failure event: rfi == 1 obs. time interval: (0, rf] exit on or before: time 60 t for analysis: time/12 ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 2,982 total observations 0 exclusions ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 2,982 observations remaining, representing 1,181 failures in single-record/single-failure data 11,130.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardized survival functions</title>
      <link>/software/stpm2_standsurv/standardized_survival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stpm2_standsurv/standardized_survival/</guid>
      <description>Background When we are performing data exploration on survival data we usually start with plotting Kaplan-Meier curves. In clinical trials with a survival outcome, one would nearly always expect to see a Kaplan-Meier curve plotted. They are simple to interpret (though there can be confusion when there are competing risks).
In observational studies, we expect that there will be confounding and would usually adjust for these confounders in a Cox model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>