<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on Paul C. Lambert</title>
    <link>/tags/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on Paul C. Lambert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Paul C Lambert</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/workshops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Full list of talks, workshops and courses</title>
      <link>/alltalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alltalks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;15-17 January 2018 Parametric Competing Risks and Multistate models, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epi-winterschool.org&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swiss Epidemiology Winter School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wengen, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22 June 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;pdf/NAACCR_Junel2017.pdf&#34;&gt;An online interactive tool to improve the understanding of cancer survival statistics&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;North American Association of Central Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Albuquerque, New Mexico, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16-19 June 2017, Cancer Survival: Principles, Methods, and Applications. Pre-conference course, &lt;em&gt;Annual meeting of North American Association of Central Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Albuquerque, New Mexico, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16-18 January 2017, Flexible Parametric Survival Models, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epi-winterschool.org&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swiss Epidemiology Winter School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wengen, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 October 2016, Beyond the hazard ratio: alternative ways to quantify dierences in survival when using flexible parametric survival models. Clinical Trials Research Unit, University of Leeds, UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 Sept 2016, 1 day course on Flexible Parametric Survival Models. &lt;em&gt;The Cancer Registry of Norway&lt;/em&gt;, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6-11 June 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Veneto, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9-11 May 2016 Statistical Methods in Epidemiology - Beyond the Cox Model, Stockholm 9-11 May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21-23 January 2016, Flexible Parametric Survival Models, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epi-winterschool.org&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swiss Epidemiology Winter School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wengen, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12 January 2016. The benefits of using parametric survival models for analysis of competing risks with time-to-event data. University of Nottingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28 October 2015. Introduction to Flexible Parametric Survival Models, Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 June 2015. Applications and developments of flexible parametric aurvival models. &lt;em&gt;Epidemiological Approaches to Evaluating Cancer Survival&lt;/em&gt;, Genova.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8-13 June 8-13 2015, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Veneto, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19-21 January 2015, Flexible Parametric Survival Models, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epi-winterschool.org&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Swiss Epidemiology Winter School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wengen, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 November 2014. Parametric modelling of the cumulative incidence function in competing risks models. University of Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28 October 2014. The use of flexible parametric survival models in epidemiology. Department of Public Health, Aarhus University, Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 September 2014. Comparison of different Approaches to estimating age standardized net survival. &lt;em&gt;Annual meeting of the Association of Nordic Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Malmo, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30 June 2014. Parametric modelling of the cumulative incidence function in competing risks models. &lt;em&gt;Statistical Analysis of Multi-Outcome Data 2014&lt;/em&gt;, University of Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16-21 June 2014, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Veneto, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 June 2014. Parametric modelling of the cumulative incidence function in competing risks models. &lt;em&gt;Fundamental Problems in Survival Analysis&lt;/em&gt;, Kings College London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 April 2014. Survival analysis: The importance of being flexible. &lt;em&gt;Scientific Seminar on Global Health and Methodology&lt;/em&gt;, University College London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18 October 2013. The many ways to report differences in cancer survival. &lt;em&gt;International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC)&lt;/em&gt;. Lyon, France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 September 2013. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stata.com/meeting/uk13/abstracts/materials/uk13_lambert.pdf&#34;&gt;Estimating and modelling cumulative incidence functions using time-dependent weights&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stata.com/meeting/uk13/&#34;&gt;UK Stata Users Group 2013&lt;/a&gt;, London UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17-22 June 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Veneto, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12-14 June 2013.How does a diagnosis of cancer affect life expectancy? Making use of the loss in expectation of life. &lt;em&gt;National Cancer Intelligence Network Cancer Outcomes Conference&lt;/em&gt;, Brighton, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;26 March 2013. Parametric Suvival Models: When should we use them? &lt;em&gt;Survival Analysis for Junior Researchers Conference&lt;/em&gt;. University of Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 March 2013. &lt;a href=&#34;pdf/Cox_40_Paul_Lambert.pdf&#34;&gt;Parametric Survival Models&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bir.biometricsociety.org/events/coxmeeting&#34;&gt;40+ years of the Cox Model&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;British and Irish Region of the International Biometric Society&lt;/em&gt;. London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 September 2012. Estimating the loss in expectation of life due to cancer using flexible parametric survival models. &lt;em&gt;34th International Association of Cancer Registries Conference&lt;/em&gt;, Cork,, Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 September 2012, Trends and projections: Age-Period-Cohort modelling using splines. Pre-conference course, &lt;em&gt;International Association of Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22 August 2012. Parametric modelling of the cumulative incidence function in competing risks models. &lt;em&gt;International Society of Clinical Biostatistics Conference 2012&lt;/em&gt;, Bergen, Norway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;June 18-22, 2012, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Veneto, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1-3 June 2012, Statistical methods for population based cancer survival analysis, Pre-conference course, &lt;em&gt;Annual meeting of North American Association of Central Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Portland, Oregon, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 November 2011. Workshop on applications and developments of flexible parametric survival models. Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;31 August 011. Measuring survival in population based cancer studies: should we be making more use of crude probabilities? &lt;em&gt;Annual meeting of the Association of Nordic Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Aland, Finland&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4-8 July 2011, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cansurv.net/&#34;&gt;Statistical methods for population-based cancer survival analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Sigtuna (Stockholm), Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29 March 2011. Useful outputs from flexible parametric survival models. &lt;em&gt;Advanced Workshop on Cancer Survival Methodology,&lt;/em&gt; London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 December 2010. Estimating the crude probabilities of death due to cancer and other causes using flexible parametric relative survival models. &lt;em&gt;XXVth International Biometric Conference&lt;/em&gt;. Florianópolis, Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 November 2010. Modelling Relative Survival: Flexible Parametric Models and the Estimation of Net and Crude Mortality. &lt;em&gt;MRC Biostatistics Unit&lt;/em&gt;, Cambridge, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22 September 2010. Long term survival: Estimation of the proportion cured. &lt;em&gt;Workshop on Combining Epidemiology &amp;amp; Economics for Measurement of Cancer Costs&lt;/em&gt;, Frascati, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 September 2010. Estimating Crude and Net Mortality in the Framework of Relative Survival. &lt;em&gt;Workshop on Methods and Applications for Population-Based Survival Workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Frascati, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 November 2009. Flexible parametric alternatives to the Cox model. &lt;em&gt;University of Birmingham&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11 September 2009. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stata.com/meeting/uk09/uk09_lambert_royston.pdf&#34;&gt;Flexible parametric alternatives to the Cox model&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;2009 UK Stata Users Group meeting&lt;/em&gt;, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 September 2009. Transferring recent advances in statistical models for relative survival to applied research. &lt;em&gt;Annual meeting of the Association of Nordic Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Sigtuna, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 September 2009, Workshop on Statistical Methods for Cancer Patient Survival., Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 June 2009. Transferring recent advances in statistical models for relative survival to applied research. &lt;em&gt;International Association of Cancer Registries, New Orleans&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1-2 June 2009, Survival Analysis For Cancer Registry Personnel, Pre-conference course at the annual meeting of the &lt;em&gt;International Association of Cancer Registries, New Orleans LA, USA&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18 March 2009. Modelling Relative Survival: Flexible Parametric Models and the Estimation of Net and Crude Mortality. &lt;em&gt;Medical Statistics Unit, London School of Hygiene &amp;amp; Tropical Medicine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19 August 2008. Estimating cumulative cause-specific mortality in the presence of other causes using relative survival models. &lt;em&gt;29th Annual Conference of the International Society for Clinical Biostatistics, Copenhagen, Denmark, August 17-21, 2008.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14 August 2008, Workshop on flexible parametric  models for survival analysis. &lt;em&gt;Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden. August 14, 2008.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22-23 November 2007, Statistical models for relative survival (with Paul Dickman). &lt;em&gt;Barcelona&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 September 2007 Fractional Polynomials and Model Averaging. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stata.com/meeting/2sweden/&#34;&gt;2nd Nordic and Baltic Stata Users Group meeting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 September 2007&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pauldickman.com/workshop/&#34;&gt;Workshop on methods for studying cancer patient survival with application in Stata&lt;/a&gt;. _Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden. _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18-20 April 2007, Relative survival: approaches to advanced modelling. &lt;em&gt;London School of Hygiene &amp;amp; Tropical Medicine.&lt;/em&gt;, London, UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February 27 - March 1 2007, Practical demographic methods in epidemiology. &lt;em&gt;Department of Biostatistics, University of Oslo&lt;/em&gt;, Oslo, Norway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modelling temporal trends in the proportion cured of disease in population based cancer studies. &lt;em&gt;Department of Social Medicine, Bristol, November 16th 2006.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6-7 November 2006, Population Based Survival Analysis. &lt;em&gt;28th Annual Meeting of the International Association of Cancer Registries&lt;/em&gt;, Goiânia, Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11-12 September 2006,&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stata.com/meeting/12uk/Stata2006PL.pdf&#34;&gt;Estimating and modelling the proportion cured of disease in population based cancer studies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;12th UK&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Stata User Group Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, London, UK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;27-31 August 2006, The estimation and modelling of the cure fraction in population based cancer studies. &lt;em&gt;27th Annual Conference of the International Society for Clinical Biostatistics&lt;/em&gt;, Geneva, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18 August 18 2006, The estimation and modelling of the cure fraction in population based cancer studies. &lt;em&gt;Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet&lt;/em&gt;, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3-7 April 2006, Cancer survival: principles, methods and applications, &lt;em&gt;London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine&lt;/em&gt;, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;29 September 2005, Extrapolation of Survival Curves Using Relative Survival Models. &lt;em&gt;Centre for Health Economics, University of York&lt;/em&gt;, York, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21-25 August 2005, Extrapolation of Survival Curves Using Relative Survival Models. &lt;em&gt;26th Annual Conference of the International Society for Clinical Biostatistics&lt;/em&gt;, Szeged, Hungary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;28 June 2005, Estimating and Modelling Cure in Population-based Cancer Survival Analysis. &lt;em&gt;Department of Medical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Karolinska Institutet&lt;/em&gt;, Stockholm, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 March 2005, Relative Survival and Excess Mortality: Application to Cancer and Coronary Heart Disease Studies. &lt;em&gt;Department of Health Sciences Seminar Series, University of Leicester&lt;/em&gt;, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15-19 August 2004. Up-to-date estimates of excess mortality using relative survival models incorporating period analysis: a comparison of models with additive and relative effects of covariates. &lt;em&gt;25th Annual Conference of the International Society for Clinical Biostatistics&lt;/em&gt;, Leiden, The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
