<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Competing Risks on Paul C. Lambert</title>
    <link>/tags/competing-risks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competing Risks on Paul C. Lambert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Paul C Lambert</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/competing-risks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>stcrprep - computational benefits</title>
      <link>/software/stcrprep/computational_benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stcrprep/computational_benefits/</guid>
      <description>When using stcrprep there are some computational benefits when compared to using Stata&amp;rsquo;s inbuilt stcrreg. One reason for this is that everytime you fit a model using stcrreg you the probability of censoring weights are calculated and the data must be expanded (in the background) when maximising the likelihood. When using stcrprep you only need to do this once.
I have run some timings. If I fit a simple model to the embt1 data with risk score as the only covariate (2 dummy variables) then these are the timings no my current work laptop (Intel i5 - running Stata 15 MP2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stcrprep</title>
      <link>/software/stcrprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stcrprep/</guid>
      <description>stcrprep prepares data for estimating and modelling cause-specific cumulative incidence functions using time-dependent weights. Once the data has been prepared and the weights incorporated using stset it is possible to obtain a graph of the non-parametric estimates of the cause-specific cumulative incidence function using sts graph. In addition a model that estimates subhazard ratios (equivalent to the Fine and Gray model) can be fitted using stcox. It is also possible to fit parametric models to directly estimate the cause-specific CIF (my main reason for developing the command).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stcrprep - non parametric cause-specific CIFs</title>
      <link>/software/stcrprep/nonparametriccif/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/stcrprep/nonparametriccif/</guid>
      <description>I will use the same data set I use in the Stata Journal article on stcrprep. This comprises of 1977 patients from the European Blood and Marrow Transplantation (EBMT) registry who received an allogeneic bone marrow transplantation. Time is measured in days from transplantation to either relapse or death. There is only one covariate of interest, the EBMT risk score, which has been categorized into 3 groups (low, medium and high risk).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>